Xbox One has ease of access features like a narrator, magnifier, and closed captioning.
Here’s how to turn them on.
Go to Settings . . . “Ease of access”.
Select an option to turn it on or off, and get information about how it works.
Narrator reads text on your screen out loud, like this.
Starting Narrator. Window. Selected: Off, one of two.
Exiting Narrator.
You don’t have to go to Settings to turn Narrator on or off.
Instead, hold the Xbox button until it vibrates, and then press the Menu button.
Magnifier zooms in to part of the screen.
The controller shortcut is similar to Narrator
hold the Xbox button, but then press the View button.
Zoom in further with the right trigger, and exit by pressing B.
Closed captioning gives you option to turn video captions on or off,
and to create a custom caption style.
High contrast changes default color and highlighting
to make text easier to read against its background.
And Button Mapping opens the Xbox Accessories app,
where you can remap the controller buttons to make the most important ones easier to use.
Select Configure, then choose Button mapping.
For example, say I don’t want to push the right bumper
for some game where I have to use it a lot.
Instead, I want to press X to get the same action.
Choose X as the button to remap,
and Right bumper as the current mapping.
Notice on the image it shows that right bumper is now mapped to X.
Discover more! Get information and tips from Xbox Help.